<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='https://michel-slm.github.io/' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
Pensées de Michel
</title>
<link>
https://michel-slm.github.io/
</link>
<description>
Michel's thoughts on software development, open source, and the meaning of life
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Tue, 03 Jan 2017 21:05:31 -0800
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
https://michel-slm.github.io/posts/2015-10-25-hypothesis-at-geekcamp/
</guid>
<link>
https://michel-slm.github.io/posts/2015-10-25-hypothesis-at-geekcamp/
</link>
<title>
Property-based Testing in Python with Hypothesis @ GeekCamp.ID
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Several months ago I discovered David R. MacIver's impressive property-based testing library for Python, &lt;a href='https://hypothesis.readthedocs.org/'&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;. Having been a big fan of Haskell's QuickCheck &amp;ndash; but not having much opportunity to use Haskell in daily life &amp;ndash; this is hugely exciting. A mature property-testing tool, targeting a popular dynamic language ... soon afterwards I &lt;a href='https://apps.fedoraproject.org/packages/python-hypothesis/overview/'&gt;packaged this library for Fedora&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; fellow Fedora users can install it with a simple&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;dnf install python-hypothesis
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;or, to specify the Python interpreter explicitly,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;dnf install python2-hypothesis
dnf install python3-hypothesis
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next step is obviously to evangelize this tool's adoption. After trialing (&quot;alpha testing&quot;) the subject at a work study session, and beta testing it at a recent Python meetup (thanks guys!), the final version of the presentation debuted at &lt;a href='http://geekcamp.id'&gt;GeekCamp.ID&lt;/a&gt; on October 24th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently the &lt;a href='https://speakerdeck.com/michelslm/property-based-testing-in-python-with-hypothesis'&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://github.com/michel-slm/talk&amp;ndash;property-based-testing&amp;ndash;hypothesis'&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; used in the talk are available; will post the link to the video recording here when it becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do check them out if you are interested, and feel free to hit me with any question on &lt;a href='https://plus.google.com/+MichelAlexandreSalim'&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/michel_slm'&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
https://michel-slm.github.io/posts/2015-08-12-phabricator-utils/
</guid>
<link>
https://michel-slm.github.io/posts/2015-08-12-phabricator-utils/
</link>
<title>
Assign Phabricator reviewers based on module ownership
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href='https://www.traveloka.com/'&gt;Traveloka&lt;/a&gt;, Indonesia's leading travel booking site, we use &lt;a href='http://phabricator.org/'&gt;Phabricator&lt;/a&gt; for code reviews - and as a growing company it might not be straightforward to figure out who is knowledgeable about a particular part of the code base and thus would be a good reviewer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Quora's &lt;a href='https://engineering.quora.com/Moving-Fast-With-High-Code-Quality'&gt;Moving Fast With High Code Quality&lt;/a&gt; post, we are thus implementing a review routing system - the code is live on GitHub at &lt;a href='https://github.com/traveloka/phabricator-utils'&gt;phabricator-utils&lt;/a&gt;. It's written in Python (hey, we're a Java/JS/Python shop), though we do plan to contribute closer to the Phabricator codebase itself and that will be in PHP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code is licensed under the Mozilla Public License version 2 - if you find it useful, contribution is welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
https://michel-slm.github.io/posts/2015-08-01-hello-cryogen/
</guid>
<link>
https://michel-slm.github.io/posts/2015-08-01-hello-cryogen/
</link>
<title>
Hello Cryogen
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning to switch to a statically-generated blog for a while, and specifically to &lt;a href='http://cryogenweb.org/'&gt;Cryogen&lt;/a&gt; hosted on &lt;a href='https://pages.github.com/'&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, for a combination of several reason:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I am already writing my posts in Markdown for  &lt;a href='https://ghost.org'&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, and prior to that,  &lt;a href='http://scriptogr.am/'&gt;Scriptogr.am&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Overhead of maintaining a Ghost blog is hosted on  &lt;a href='https://www.openshift.com/products/online'&gt;OpenShift Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I prefer Clojure to JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cryogen developer &lt;a href='https://github.com/lacarmen'&gt;lacarmen&lt;/a&gt; is  amazingly responsive. This  &lt;a href='https://github.com/cryogen-project/cryogen/issues/44'&gt;request for tag-specific RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;  is done within a day. Ghost dragged its feet on this.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will set up Disqus integration later &amp;ndash; and need to work on a better-looking site theme too, but that can wait. For now, hello!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
